<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://www.fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd"><metadata>	<idinfo>		<citation>			<citeinfo>				<origin>Tele Atlas (Firm : U.S.)</origin>				<origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</origin>				<pubdate>20100630</pubdate>				<title>Major Highways U.S.A. 2002</title>				<edition>10</edition>				<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>				<serinfo>					<sername>ESRI Data &amp; Maps</sername>					<issue>10 - World, Europe, and United States</issue>				</serinfo>				<pubinfo>					<pubplace>Redlands (Calif.)</pubplace>					<publish>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</publish>				</pubinfo>				<othercit>Location: \usa\trans</othercit>				<onlink>http://www.arcgis.com/home/group.html?owner=esri&amp;title=ESRI%20Data%20%26%20Maps&amp;content=all</onlink>				<lworkcit>					<citeinfo>						<origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</origin>						<origin>Michael Bauer Research (Firm : Germany)</origin>						<pubdate>2010</pubdate>						<title>ESRI Data and Maps 10</title>						<pubinfo>							<pubplace>Redlands (Calif.)</pubplace>							<publish>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</publish>						</pubinfo>					</citeinfo>				</lworkcit>				<ftname Sync="TRUE">USHighwaymjr02</ftname></citeinfo>		</citation>		<descript>			<abstract>This line file represents the major highways of the United States. These include interstates, U.S. highways, state highways, and major roads. This dataset is from the Census 2000 TIGER/Line files. It contains all Class 1 and 2 roads segments plus any other road segments necessary to provide network connectivity for the Class_Rte field.</abstract>			<purpose>This layer is intended for researchers, students, and policy makers for reference and mapping purposes, and may be used for basic applications such as viewing, querying, and map output production, or to provide a basemap to support graphical overlays and analysis with other spatial data.</purpose>			<supplinf>Largest scale when displaying the data: 1:100,000.</supplinf>			<langdata Sync="TRUE">en</langdata></descript>		<timeperd>			<timeinfo>				<sngdate>					<caldate>2002</caldate>				</sngdate>			</timeinfo>			<current>ground condition</current>		</timeperd>		<status>			<progress>Complete</progress>			<update>Annually</update>		</status>		<spdom>			<bounding>				<westbc>-159.779918</westbc>				<eastbc>-66.981845</eastbc>				<northbc>65.826906</northbc>				<southbc>19.058082</southbc>			</bounding>			<lboundng><leftbc Sync="TRUE">-159.779918</leftbc><rightbc Sync="TRUE">-66.981845</rightbc><bottombc Sync="TRUE">19.058082</bottombc><topbc Sync="TRUE">65.826906</topbc></lboundng></spdom>		<keywords>			<theme>				<themekt>FGDC</themekt>				<themekey>line</themekey>			</theme>			<theme>				<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>				<themekey>transportation</themekey>			</theme>			<theme>				<themekt>FGDC</themekt>				<themekey>roads</themekey>			</theme>			<place>				<placekt>GNIS</placekt>				<placekey>United States</placekey>			</place>			<place>				<placekt>LCNH</placekt>				<placekey>Northern Hemisphere</placekey>				<placekey>Western Hemisphere</placekey>				<placekey>North America</placekey>			</place>		</keywords>		<accconst>Restricted Access Online: Access granted to Licensee only. Available only to Tufts University affiliates.</accconst>		<useconst>The data are provided by multiple, third party data vendors under license to ESRI for inclusion on ESRI Data &amp; Maps for use with ESRI software.  Each data vendor has its own data licensing policies and may grant varying redistribution rights to end users. Please consult the redistribution rights below for this data set provided on ESRI Data &amp; Maps. As used herein, Geodata shall mean any digital data set consisting of geographic data coordinates and associated attributes.The redistribution rights for this data set: Redistribution rights are granted by the data vendor for hard-copy renditions or static, electronic map images (e.g. .gif, .jpeg, etc.) that are plotted, printed, or publicly displayed with proper metadata and source/copyright attribution to the respective data vendor(s).  Geodata is redistributable with a Value-Added Software Application developed by ESRI Business Partners on a royalty-free basis with proper metadata and source/copyright attribution to the respective data vendor(s).  Geodata is redistributable without a Value-Added Software Application (i.e., adding the sample data to an existing, [non]commercial data set for redistribution) with proper metadata and source/copyright attribution to the respective data vendor(s).The terms and conditions below apply to all the data sets provided on ESRI Data &amp; Maps.Proprietary Rights and Copyright: Licensee acknowledges that the Data and Related Materials contain proprietary and confidential property of ESRI and its licensor(s). The Data and Related Materials are owned by ESRI and its licensor(s) and are protected by United States copyright laws and applicable international copyright treaties and/or conventions.Limited Warranty and Disclaimer: ESRI warrants that the media upon which the Data and Related Materials are provided will be free from defects in materials and workmanship under normal use and service for a period of ninety (90) days from the date of receipt.THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE EXCLUDED FROM THE LIMITED WARRANTY, AND THE LICENSEE EXPRESSLY ACKNOWLEDGES THAT THE DATA CONTAINS SOME NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS. ESRI DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE DATA WILL MEET LICENSEE'S NEEDS OR EXPECTATIONS; THAT THE USE OF THE DATA WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED; OR THAT ALL NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS CAN OR WILL BE CORRECTED. ESRI IS NOT INVITING RELIANCE ON THIS DATA, AND THE LICENSEE SHOULD ALWAYS VERIFY ACTUAL DATA.EXCEPT FOR THE LIMITED WARRANTY SET FORTH ABOVE, THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS CONTAINED THEREIN ARE PROVIDED "AS-IS," WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES: (A) THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE NOT FAULT-TOLERANT AND ARE NOT DESIGNED, MANUFACTURED, OR INTENDED FOR USE OR RESALE FOR INSURANCE UNDERWRITING OR WITH CRITICAL HEALTH AND SAFETY OR ONLINE CONTROL EQUIPMENT IN HAZARDOUS ENVIRONMENTS THAT REQUIRE FAIL-SAFE PERFORMANCE, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE OPERATION OF NUCLEAR FACILITIES, NAVIGATION OR GUIDANCE (I.E., AIRCRAFT, NAUTICAL VEHICLE, ETC.), OR COMMUNICATION SYSTEMS, AIR TRAFFIC CONTROL, EMERGENCY RESPONSE, TERRORISM PREVENTION OR RESPONSE, LIFE SUPPORT, OR WEAPONS SYSTEMS ("HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES"). ESRI SPECIFICALLY DISCLAIMS ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTY OF FITNESS FOR HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES.(B) TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW, LICENSEE AGREES TO INDEMNIFY, DEFEND, AND HOLD ESRI, ITS OFFICERS, DIRECTORS, EMPLOYEES, AGENTS, SUBCONTRACTORS, LICENSORS, SUCCESSORS, AND ASSIGNS HARMLESS FROM AND AGAINST ANY AND ALL LIABILITY, LOSSES, CLAIMS, EXPENSES (INCLUDING ATTORNEYS' FEES), DEMANDS, OR DAMAGES OF ANY KIND, INCLUDING DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, PUNITIVE, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, ARISING OUT OF OR IN ANY WAY CONNECTED WITH LICENSEE'S USE OR PERMITTING THE USE BY OTHERS OF THE DATA, AND VENDOR'S HARDWARE OR SOFTWARE FOR HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES. DELIVERY OF THE DATA, AND VENDOR'S HARDWARE OR SOFTWARE DOES NOT CONSTITUTE A WAIVER OF THE RIGHTS AND OBLIGATIONS SET FORTH IN THIS ARTICLE.Exclusive Remedy and Limitation of Liability: The entire liability of ESRI or its licensor(s) and Licensee's exclusive remedy shall be to terminate the Agreement upon Licensee returning the Data and Related Materials to ESRI with a copy of Licensee's invoice/receipt and ESRI returning the license fees paid to Licensee.IN NO EVENT SHALL ESRI AND/OR ITS LICENSOR(S) BE LIABLE FOR COSTS OF PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOST PROFITS, LOST SALES, OR BUSINESS EXPENDITURES, INVESTMENTS, OR COMMITMENTS IN CONNECTION WITH ANY BUSINESS; LOSS OF ANY GOODWILL; OR FOR ANY INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THIS AGREEMENT OR USE OF THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS, HOWEVER CAUSED, ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, AND WHETHER OR NOT ESRI OR ITS LICENSOR(S) HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE. THESE LIMITATIONS SHALL APPLY NOTWITHSTANDING ANY FAILURE OF ESSENTIAL PURPOSE OF ANY EXCLUSIVE REMEDY.Third Party Beneficiary: ESRI's licensor(s) has (have) authorized ESRI to (sub)distribute and (sub)license its (their) data as incorporated into the Data and Related Materials. As an intended third party beneficiary to this Agreement, the ESRI licensor(s) is (are) entitled to directly enforce, in its own name, the rights and obligations undertaken by the Licensee and to seek all legal and equitable remedies as are afforded to ESRI.In the event that the data vendor(s) has (have) granted the end user permission to redistribute the Geodata, please use proper proprietary or copyright attribution for the various data vendor(s), and provide the associated metadata file(s) with the Geodata. In compliance with FGDC metadata standards, ESRI has attempted to practice proper metadata methodologies by providing any data source information, descriptions, and file names to assist in this effort.</useconst>		<ptcontac>			<cntinfo>				<cntorgp>					<cntorg>ESRI</cntorg>					<cntper>ArcGIS Content Team</cntper>				</cntorgp>				<cntaddr>					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>					<address>380 New York Street</address>					<city>Redlands</city>					<state>California</state>					<postal>92373-8100</postal>					<country>USA</country>				</cntaddr>				<cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>				<cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>				<cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>				<hours>7:00 a.m.5:30 p.m. Pacific time, MondayFriday</hours>				<cntinst>In the United StatesPlease direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local ESRI Regional Office.  For support, you may contact ESRI Support Center by telephone (voice) between 5:00 a.m. and 5:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing 888-377-4575; facsimile (fax) available at 909-792-0960; electronic mail (e-mail) support@esri.com; or visit http://support.esri.com/; ESRI holidays excluded. Outside the United StatesPlease direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local ESRI Office.  This information can be found at http://www.esri.com/company/locations.html.  For other questions or comments, you may contact ESRI headquarters by e-mail, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>			</cntinfo>		</ptcontac>		<native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 2; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.0.1770</native>		<natvform Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</natvform></idinfo>	<dataqual>		<logic>The shapefile is converted to SDC (Smart Data Compression) format using either tools in ArcGIS or ESRI SDC Data Development Kit Professional 2 (DDKP2).  The SDC data set is then imported into a file geodatabase to verify and validate the geometry.</logic>		<complete>After processing, the data set is checked for drawing display and number of records and file sizes compared with source materials.</complete>		<posacc>			<horizpa>				<horizpar>The geospatial part of this data set was extracted from the Census 2000 TIGER/Line files. The positional accuracy varies with the source materials used, but generally the information is no better than the established national map Accuracy standards for 1:100,000-scale maps from the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS). To improve the accuracy, Tele Atlas ran a process against the entire nationwide database.The level of positional accuracy in the StreetMap files is not suitable for high-precision measurement applications such as engineering problems, property transfers, or other uses that might require highly accurate measurements of the earth's surface.</horizpar>			</horizpa>		</posacc>		<lineage>			<srcinfo>				<srccite>					<citeinfo>						<origin>Tele Atlas North America, Inc.</origin>						<pubdate>2002</pubdate>						<title>Tele Atlas TIGER/Line 2000 Streets</title>						<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>						<pubinfo>							<pubplace>Lebanon, New Hampshire, USA</pubplace>							<publish>Tele Atlas North America, Inc.</publish>						</pubinfo>						<othercit>TIGER/Line 2000 Data Processed by a proprietary line straightening process by Tele Atlas North America, Inc.</othercit>					</citeinfo>				</srccite>				<srcscale>100000</srcscale>				<typesrc>CDROM</typesrc>				<srctime>					<timeinfo>						<sngdate>							<caldate>2000</caldate>						</sngdate>					</timeinfo>					<srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>				</srctime>				<srccitea>Tele Atlas TIGER/Line Streets</srccitea>				<srccontr>Attribute and geospatial data</srccontr>			</srcinfo>			<srcinfo>				<srccite>					<citeinfo>						<origin>ESRI</origin>						<title>ArcGIS Resource Centers ArcGIS Online services - USA Prime Imagery</title>						<geoform>raster digital data</geoform>						<pubinfo>							<pubplace>Redlands, California, USA</pubplace>							<publish>ESRI</publish>						</pubinfo>						<othercit>Accessed the map service in August 2008. Copyright:  2008 i-cubed; i-cubed, Ft. Collins, CO, USA</othercit>						<onlink>http://resources.esri.com/arcgisonlineservices/index.cfm?fa=content_detail&amp;contentID=F7EE515D-1422-2413-199DAEFAA2B134F9</onlink>					</citeinfo>				</srccite>				<typesrc>online</typesrc>				<srccitea>ESRI ArcGIS Resource Centers ArcGIS Online services - USA Prime Imagery</srccitea>				<srccontr>Geospatial data</srccontr>			</srcinfo>			<procstep>				<procdesc>The following steps were performed by ESRI: From StreetMap Detailed Streets, extracted all Class 1 and 2 road segments plus any other road segments necessary to provide network connectivity for the CLASS_RTE attribute. Converted the data set to SDC. Created the projection file (.prj) and spatial indices.</procdesc>				<srcused>Tele Atlas TIGER/Line Streets</srcused>				<procdate>20031212</procdate>			</procstep>			<procstep>				<procdesc>The following steps were performed by ESRI: For all features where attributes HWY_TYPE is equal to "" and PRETYPE is not equal to "", manually corrected the HWY_TYPE and HWY_SYMBOL values for county, state, U.S., and interstate highways.  For example, if attributes PRETYPE equals "I" and NAME equals "91", made HWY_TYPE equal to "I" and HWY_SYMBOL equal to "91".  Converted the data set to SDC.  Created ArcGIS layer file (.lyr), projection file (.prj), and spatial indices.</procdesc>				<srcused>Tele Atlas TIGER/Line Streets</srcused>				<procdate>20060419</procdate>			</procstep>			<procstep>				<procdesc>The following steps were performed by ESRI: Corrected a few known errors.  Converted the data set to SDC. Created ArcGIS layer file (.lyr), projection file (.prj), and spatial indices.</procdesc>				<srcused>ESRI ArcGIS Resource Centers ArcGIS Online services - USA Prime Imagery</srcused>				<procdate>20081002</procdate>			</procstep>			<procstep>				<procdesc>The following changes were made:File name changed from mjr_hwys to USHighwaymjr10.Larger Work Citation was added.Keywords and placenames were altered to reflect FGDC standards.Use Constraints, Access, Distribution Liability, Resource, Ordering instructions, Fees, and Contact information were changed to reflect Tufts University requirements.</procdesc>				<procdate>201112</procdate>				<proccont>					<cntinfo>						<cntorgp>							<cntorg>Tufts University GIS Center</cntorg>						</cntorgp>						<cntaddr>							<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>							<address>Academic Technology</address>							<address>16 Dearborn Rd</address>							<city>Somerville</city>							<state>MA</state>							<postal>02144</postal>							<country>USA</country>						</cntaddr>						<cntvoice>617-627-3380</cntvoice>						<cntemail>gis-support@elist.tufts.edu</cntemail>						<hours>Monday-Friday, 9:00 AM- 5:00 PM, EST-USA</hours>					</cntinfo>				</proccont>			</procstep>			<procstep>				<procdesc>Dataset copied.</procdesc>				<srcused />				<procdate>20120511</procdate>				<proctime>10004000</proctime>			</procstep>		</lineage>	</dataqual>	<spdoinfo>		<direct>Vector</direct>		<ptvctinf>			<sdtsterm Name="USHighwaymjr02">				<sdtstype>String</sdtstype>				<ptvctcnt>171613</ptvctcnt>			</sdtsterm>			<esriterm Name="USHighwaymjr02"><efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp><efeageom Sync="TRUE">Polyline</efeageom><esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo><efeacnt Sync="TRUE">171613</efeacnt><spindex Sync="TRUE">TRUE</spindex><linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer></esriterm></ptvctinf>	</spdoinfo>	<spref>		<horizsys>			<geograph>				<latres>0.000000</latres>				<longres>0.000000</longres>				<geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>			</geograph>			<geodetic>				<horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn>				<ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>				<semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>				<denflat>298.257224</denflat>			</geodetic>			<cordsysn><geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_WGS_1984</geogcsn></cordsysn></horizsys>	</spref>	<eainfo>		<detailed Name="USHighwaymjr02">			<enttyp>				<enttypl>mjr_hwys</enttypl>				<enttypd>The lines represent the major highways of the United States. These include interstates, U.S. highways, state highways, and major roads.</enttypd>				<enttypds>ESRI</enttypds>				<enttypt Sync="TRUE">Feature Class</enttypt><enttypc Sync="TRUE">171613</enttypc></enttyp>			<attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">FID</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">FID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">OID</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef Sync="TRUE">Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs Sync="TRUE">ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom Sync="TRUE">Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr>				<attrlabl>ObjectID</attrlabl>				<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">ObjectID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Number</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">9</attwidth></attr>			<attr>				<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>				<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Geometry</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>			<attr>				<attrlabl>PREFIX</attrlabl>				<attrdef>The prefix direction.</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<udom>Prefix directions of the address attributes for the features.</udom>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">PREFIX</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">2</attwidth></attr>			<attr>				<attrlabl>PRETYPE</attrlabl>				<attrdef>The prefix highway type.</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<udom>Prefix highway types of the address attributes for the features.</udom>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">PRETYPE</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">6</attwidth></attr>			<attr>				<attrlabl>NAME</attrlabl>				<attrdef>The name or route number of the highway.</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Tele Atlas (Firm : U.S.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<udom>Names for the features.</udom>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">NAME</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">30</attwidth></attr>			<attr>				<attrlabl>TYPE</attrlabl>				<attrdef>The suffix highway type.</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<udom>Suffix highway types of the address attributes for the features.</udom>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">TYPE</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">6</attwidth></attr>			<attr>				<attrlabl>SUFFIX</attrlabl>				<attrdef>The suffix direction.</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<udom>Suffix directions of the address attributes for the features.</udom>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">SUFFIX</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">2</attwidth></attr>			<attr>				<attrlabl>CLASS</attrlabl>				<attrdef>The highway class.</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<edom>						<edomv>1</edomv>						<edomvd>Limited Access.</edomvd>						<edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>2</edomv>						<edomvd>Highway.</edomvd>						<edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>3</edomv>						<edomvd>Major Road.</edomvd>						<edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>4</edomv>						<edomvd>Local Road.</edomvd>						<edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>5</edomv>						<edomvd>Minor Road.</edomvd>						<edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>6</edomv>						<edomvd>Other Road.</edomvd>						<edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>7</edomv>						<edomvd>Ramp.</edomvd>						<edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>8</edomv>						<edomvd>Ferry.</edomvd>						<edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>9</edomv>						<edomvd>Pedestrian Way.</edomvd>						<edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>					</edom>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">CLASS</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">1</attwidth></attr>			<attr>				<attrlabl>CLASS_RTE</attrlabl>				<attrdef>The highway class (used for routing and connectivity).</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<edom>						<edomv>1</edomv>						<edomvd>Limited Access.</edomvd>						<edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>2</edomv>						<edomvd>Highway.</edomvd>						<edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>3</edomv>						<edomvd>Major Road.</edomvd>						<edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>4</edomv>						<edomvd>Local Road.</edomvd>						<edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>5</edomv>						<edomvd>Minor Road.</edomvd>						<edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>6</edomv>						<edomvd>Other Road.</edomvd>						<edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>7</edomv>						<edomvd>Ramp.</edomvd>						<edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>8</edomv>						<edomvd>Ferry.</edomvd>						<edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>9</edomv>						<edomvd>Pedestrian Way.</edomvd>						<edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>0</edomv>						<edomvd>A special class of highway to do very fast high level cross-country routing that also selects the through-route in complicated urban areas.</edomvd>						<edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>					</edom>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">CLASS_RTE</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">1</attwidth></attr>			<attr>				<attrlabl>HWY_TYPE</attrlabl>				<attrdef>The highway type.</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<edom>						<edomv>I</edomv>						<edomvd>Interstate.</edomvd>						<edomvds>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>U</edomv>						<edomvd>U.S. highway.</edomvd>						<edomvds>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>S</edomv>						<edomvd>State highway.</edomvd>						<edomvds>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>C</edomv>						<edomvd>County highway.</edomvd>						<edomvds>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>H</edomv>						<edomvd>Highway (type unknown).</edomvd>						<edomvds>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>&lt;blank&gt;</edomv>						<edomvd>None of the above.</edomvd>						<edomvds>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</edomvds>					</edom>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">HWY_TYPE</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">1</attwidth></attr>			<attr>				<attrlabl>HWY_SYMBOL</attrlabl>				<attrdef>The highway symbol (usually route number).</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">HWY_SYMBOL</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">20</attwidth></attr>		</detailed>	</eainfo>	<distinfo>		<distrib>			<cntinfo>				<cntorgp>					<cntorg>Tufts University GIS Center</cntorg>				</cntorgp>				<cntpos>Data Technician</cntpos>				<cntaddr>					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>					<address>Academic Technology</address>					<address>16 Dearborn Rd</address>					<city>Somerville</city>					<state>MA</state>					<postal>02144</postal>					<country>USA</country>				</cntaddr>				<cntvoice>617-627-3380</cntvoice>				<cntemail>gis-support@elist.tufts.edu</cntemail>				<hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 5:00 pm EST-USA</hours>			</cntinfo>		</distrib>		<resdesc>Online Dataset</resdesc>		<distliab>Although this data is being distributed by Tufts University, no warranty expressed or implied is made by the University as to the accuracy of the data and related materials. The act of distribution shall not constitute any such warranty, and no responsibility is assumed by the University in the use of this data, or related materials.</distliab>		<stdorder>			<digform>				<digtinfo>					<formname>SDC</formname>					<formspec>The SDC file contains the geospatial and attribute data. The SDI file contains the spatial index. The PRJ file contains the coordinate system information (optional). The XML file (*.sdc.xml) contains the metadata describing the data set (optional).</formspec>					<filedec>ArcGIS software</filedec>					<transize>22.547</transize>					<dssize Sync="TRUE">91.127</dssize></digtinfo>				<digtopt>					<offoptn>						<offmedia>DVDROM</offmedia>						<reccap>							<recden>4.38 or 7.95</recden>							<recdenu>GB (gigabytes)</recdenu>						</reccap>						<recfmt>UDF (Universal Disc Format)</recfmt>					</offoptn>				</digtopt>			</digform>			<fees>none</fees>			<ordering>Web-based Distribution Only</ordering>		</stdorder>		<techpreq>To use this data requires software that supports SDC files.</techpreq>	</distinfo>	<metainfo>		<metd>20120430</metd>		<metc>			<cntinfo>				<cntorgp>					<cntorg>Tufts University GIS Center</cntorg>				</cntorgp>				<cntpos>Data Technician</cntpos>				<cntaddr>					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>					<address>Academic Technology</address>					<address>16 Dearborn Rd</address>					<city>Somerville</city>					<state>MA</state>					<postal>02144</postal>					<country>USA</country>				</cntaddr>				<cntvoice>617-627-3380</cntvoice>				<cntemail>gis-supports@elits.tufts.edu</cntemail>				<hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 5:00 pm EST-USA</hours>			</cntinfo>		</metc>		<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>		<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>		<mettc>local time</mettc>		<metextns>			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>		</metextns>		<langmeta Sync="TRUE">en</langmeta><metextns><onlink Sync="TRUE">http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink><metprof Sync="TRUE">ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof></metextns></metainfo>	<dataIdInfo><envirDesc Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows Vista Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.4000</envirDesc><dataLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en" /></dataLang><idCitation><resTitle Sync="TRUE">USHighwaymjr02</resTitle><presForm><PresFormCd Sync="TRUE" value="005" /></presForm></idCitation><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001" /></spatRpType><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox esriExtentType="native"><westBL Sync="TRUE">-159.779918</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-66.981845</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">65.826906</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">19.058082</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt><geoBox esriExtentType="decdegrees"><westBL Sync="TRUE">-159.779918</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-66.981845</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">65.826906</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">19.058082</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></geoBox></dataIdInfo><mdLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en" /></mdLang><mdStanName Sync="TRUE">ISO 19115 Geographic Information - Metadata</mdStanName><mdStanVer Sync="TRUE">DIS_ESRI1.0</mdStanVer><mdChar><CharSetCd Sync="TRUE" value="004" /></mdChar><mdHrLv><ScopeCd Sync="TRUE" value="005" /></mdHrLv><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName><distInfo><distributor><distorTran><onLineSrc><orDesc Sync="TRUE">002</orDesc><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\rstore2\gisprojects$\GIS_Center_Projects\EnterpriseGIS\Layers\ESRIDataaandMaps 10\esri shapefiles\USHighwaymjr02.shp</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></onLineSrc><transSize Sync="TRUE">91.127</transSize></distorTran><distorFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><refSysInfo><RefSystem><refSysID><identCode Sync="TRUE">GCS_WGS_1984</identCode></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo><spatRepInfo><VectSpatRep><topLvl><TopoLevCd Sync="TRUE" value="001" /></topLvl><geometObjs Name="USHighwaymjr02"><geoObjTyp><GeoObjTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001" /></geoObjTyp><geoObjCnt Sync="TRUE">171613</geoObjCnt></geometObjs></VectSpatRep></spatRepInfo><Esri><SyncDate>20120521</SyncDate><SyncTime>16380200</SyncTime><ModDate>20120521</ModDate><ModTime>16380200</ModTime></Esri><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20120521</mdDateSt></metadata>