<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?><!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://www.fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd"><metadata>	<idinfo>		<citation>			<citeinfo>				<origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</origin>				<pubdate>20100630</pubdate>				<title>USGS 1:100,000 Topographic Quadrangle Series Index U.S.A. 1975-1992</title>				<edition>10</edition>				<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>				<serinfo>					<sername>ESRI Data &amp;amp; Maps</sername>					<issue>10 - World, Europe, and United States</issue>				</serinfo>				<pubinfo>					<pubplace>Redlands (Calif.)</pubplace>					<publish>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</publish>				</pubinfo>				<othercit>Location: \usa\other</othercit>				<onlink>http://www.arcgis.com/home/group.html?owner=esri&amp;amp;title=ESRI%20Data%20%26%20Maps&amp;amp;content=all</onlink>				<lworkcit>					<citeinfo>						<origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</origin>						<origin>Michael Bauer Research (Firm : Germany)</origin>						<pubdate>2010</pubdate>						<title>ESRI Data and Maps 10</title>						<edition>10</edition>						<pubinfo>							<pubplace>Redlands (Calif.)</pubplace>							<publish>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</publish>						</pubinfo>					</citeinfo>				</lworkcit>				<ftname Sync="TRUE">USTopoq1007592</ftname></citeinfo>		</citation>		<descript>			<abstract>This polygon shapefile represents the geographic extent of USGS 1:100,000 topographic maps (30- by 60-minute quadrangles) for the coterminous U.S. forty-eight states and District of Columbia.</abstract>			<purpose>This layer is intended for researchers, students, and policy makers for reference and mapping purposes, and may be used for basic applications such as viewing, querying, and map output production, or to provide a basemap to support graphical overlays and analysis with other spatial data.</purpose>			<langdata Sync="TRUE">en</langdata></descript>		<timeperd>			<timeinfo>				<rngdates>					<begdate>1975?1986</begdate>					<enddate>1992</enddate>				</rngdates>			</timeinfo>			<current>ground condition</current>		</timeperd>		<status>			<progress>Complete</progress>			<update>Annually</update>		</status>		<spdom>			<bounding>				<westbc>-125.000027</westbc>				<eastbc>-66.000000</eastbc>				<northbc>49.500009</northbc>				<southbc>24.500000</southbc>			</bounding>			<lboundng><leftbc Sync="TRUE">-125.000027</leftbc><rightbc Sync="TRUE">-66.000005</rightbc><bottombc Sync="TRUE">24.500000</bottombc><topbc Sync="TRUE">49.500002</topbc></lboundng></spdom>		<keywords>			<theme>				<themekt>FGDC</themekt>				<themekey>polygon</themekey>			</theme>			<theme>				<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>				<themekey>boundaries</themekey>			</theme>			<theme>				<themekt>LCSH</themekt>				<themekey>United States</themekey>				<themekey>Topographic Maps</themekey>			</theme>			<place>				<placekt>GNIS</placekt>				<placekey>United States</placekey>			</place>			<place>				<placekt>LCNH</placekt>				<placekey>Northern Hemisphere</placekey>				<placekey>Western Hemisphere</placekey>				<placekey>North America</placekey>			</place>		</keywords>		<accconst>Restricted Access Online: Access granted to Licensee only. Available only to Tufts University affiliates.</accconst>		<useconst>The data are provided by multiple, third party data vendors under license to ESRI for inclusion on ESRI Data &amp;amp; Maps for use with ESRI software.  Each data vendor has its own data licensing policies and may grant varying redistribution rights to end users. Please consult the redistribution rights below for this data set provided on ESRI Data &amp;amp; Maps. As used herein, ?Geodata? shall mean any digital data set consisting of geographic data coordinates and associated attributes.The redistribution rights for this data set: Redistribution rights are granted by the data vendor for hard-copy renditions or static, electronic map images (e.g. .gif, .jpeg, etc.) that are plotted, printed, or publicly displayed with proper metadata and source/copyright attribution to the respective data vendor(s).  Geodata is redistributable with a Value-Added Software Application developed by ESRI Business Partners on a royalty-free basis with proper metadata and source/copyright attribution to the respective data vendor(s). Geodata is redistributable without a Value-Added Software Application (i.e., adding the sample data to an existing, [non]commercial data set for redistribution) with proper metadata and source/copyright attribution to the respective data vendor(s). The terms and conditions below apply to all the data sets provided on ESRI Data &amp;amp; Maps.Proprietary Rights and Copyright: Licensee acknowledges that the Data and Related Materials contain proprietary and confidential property of ESRI and its licensor(s). The Data and Related Materials are owned by ESRI and its licensor(s) and are protected by United States copyright laws and applicable international copyright treaties and/or conventions.Limited Warranty and Disclaimer: ESRI warrants that the media upon which the Data and Related Materials are provided will be free from defects in materials and workmanship under normal use and service for a period of ninety (90) days from the date of receipt.THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE EXCLUDED FROM THE LIMITED WARRANTY, AND THE LICENSEE EXPRESSLY ACKNOWLEDGES THAT THE DATA CONTAINS SOME NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS. ESRI DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE DATA WILL MEET LICENSEE'S NEEDS OR EXPECTATIONS; THAT THE USE OF THE DATA WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED; OR THAT ALL NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS CAN OR WILL BE CORRECTED. ESRI IS NOT INVITING RELIANCE ON THIS DATA, AND THE LICENSEE SHOULD ALWAYS VERIFY ACTUAL DATA.EXCEPT FOR THE LIMITED WARRANTY SET FORTH ABOVE, THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS CONTAINED THEREIN ARE PROVIDED "AS-IS," WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES: (A) THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE NOT FAULT-TOLERANT AND ARE NOT DESIGNED, MANUFACTURED, OR INTENDED FOR USE OR RESALE FOR INSURANCE UNDERWRITING OR WITH CRITICAL HEALTH AND SAFETY OR ONLINE CONTROL EQUIPMENT IN HAZARDOUS ENVIRONMENTS THAT REQUIRE FAIL-SAFE PERFORMANCE, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE OPERATION OF NUCLEAR FACILITIES, NAVIGATION OR GUIDANCE (I.E., AIRCRAFT, NAUTICAL VEHICLE, ETC.), OR COMMUNICATION SYSTEMS, AIR TRAFFIC CONTROL, EMERGENCY RESPONSE, TERRORISM PREVENTION OR RESPONSE, LIFE SUPPORT, OR WEAPONS SYSTEMS ("HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES"). ESRI SPECIFICALLY DISCLAIMS ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTY OF FITNESS FOR HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES.(B) TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW, LICENSEE AGREES TO INDEMNIFY, DEFEND, AND HOLD ESRI, ITS OFFICERS, DIRECTORS, EMPLOYEES, AGENTS, SUBCONTRACTORS, LICENSORS, SUCCESSORS, AND ASSIGNS HARMLESS FROM AND AGAINST ANY AND ALL LIABILITY, LOSSES, CLAIMS, EXPENSES (INCLUDING ATTORNEYS' FEES), DEMANDS, OR DAMAGES OF ANY KIND, INCLUDING DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, PUNITIVE, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, ARISING OUT OF OR IN ANY WAY CONNECTED WITH LICENSEE'S USE OR PERMITTING THE USE BY OTHERS OF THE DATA, AND VENDOR'S HARDWARE OR SOFTWARE FOR HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES. DELIVERY OF THE DATA, AND VENDOR'S HARDWARE OR SOFTWARE DOES NOT CONSTITUTE A WAIVER OF THE RIGHTS AND OBLIGATIONS SET FORTH IN THIS ARTICLE.Exclusive Remedy and Limitation of Liability: The entire liability of ESRI or its licensor(s) and Licensee's exclusive remedy shall be to terminate the Agreement upon Licensee returning the Data and Related Materials to ESRI with a copy of Licensee's invoice/receipt and ESRI returning the license fees paid to Licensee.IN NO EVENT SHALL ESRI AND/OR ITS LICENSOR(S) BE LIABLE FOR COSTS OF PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOST PROFITS, LOST SALES, OR BUSINESS EXPENDITURES, INVESTMENTS, OR COMMITMENTS IN CONNECTION WITH ANY BUSINESS; LOSS OF ANY GOODWILL; OR FOR ANY INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THIS AGREEMENT OR USE OF THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS, HOWEVER CAUSED, ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, AND WHETHER OR NOT ESRI OR ITS LICENSOR(S) HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE. THESE LIMITATIONS SHALL APPLY NOTWITHSTANDING ANY FAILURE OF ESSENTIAL PURPOSE OF ANY EXCLUSIVE REMEDY.Third Party Beneficiary: ESRI's licensor(s) has (have) authorized ESRI to (sub)distribute and (sub)license its (their) data as incorporated into the Data and Related Materials. As an intended third party beneficiary to this Agreement, the ESRI licensor(s) is (are) entitled to directly enforce, in its own name, the rights and obligations undertaken by the Licensee and to seek all legal and equitable remedies as are afforded to ESRI.In the event that the data vendor(s) has (have) granted the end user permission to redistribute the Geodata, please use proper proprietary or copyright attribution for the various data vendor(s), and provide the associated metadata file(s) with the Geodata. In compliance with FGDC metadata standards, ESRI has attempted to practice proper metadata methodologies by providing any data source information, descriptions, and file names to assist in this effort.</useconst>		<ptcontac>			<cntinfo>				<cntorgp>					<cntorg>ESRI</cntorg>					<cntper>ArcGIS Content Team</cntper>				</cntorgp>				<cntaddr>					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>					<address>380 New York Street</address>					<city>Redlands</city>					<state>California</state>					<postal>92373-8100</postal>					<country>USA</country>				</cntaddr>				<cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>				<cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>				<cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>				<hours>7:00 a.m.?5:30 p.m. Pacific time, Monday?Friday</hours>				<cntinst>In the United States?Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing and consulting services to your local ESRI Regional Office.  For support, you may contact ESRI Support Center by telephone (voice) between 5:00 a.m. and 5:00 p.m. Pacific time, Monday through Friday, by dialing 888-377-4575; facsimile (fax) available at 909-792-0960; electronic mail (e-mail) support@esri.com; or visit http://support.esri.com/; ESRI holidays excluded. Outside the United States?Please direct all inquiries regarding software/data pricing, sales, support, and consulting services to your local ESRI Office.  This information can be found at http://www.esri.com/company/locations.html.  For other questions or comments, you may contact ESRI headquarters by e-mail, telephone, or fax or write to us.</cntinst>			</cntinfo>		</ptcontac>		<datacred>United States Geological Survey</datacred>		<native>Microsoft Windows 2000 Version 5.0 (Build 2195) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 8.3.0.800</native>		<natvform Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</natvform></idinfo>	<dataqual>		<logic>The shapefile is converted to SDC (Smart Data Compression) format using either tools in ArcGIS or ESRI SDC Data Development Kit Professional 2 (DDKP2).  The SDC data set is then imported into a file geodatabase to verify and validate the geometry. Occasionally, USGS actual quadrangles depart from a completely rectangular format mainly because of map sheet production considerations in coastal areas and offshore islands that result in rotation, offset, over edge, and inset sheet layouts. These are not represented precisely by the data set, but the correct attribute information is included.</logic>		<complete>After processing, the data set is checked for drawing display and number of records and file sizes compared with source materials.</complete>		<posacc>			<horizpa>				<horizpar>The geospatial part of this data set was mathematically generated using the ARC/INFO GRID? extension.  In this manner, the locations of the quadrangles were computed.  The positional accuracy for these quadrangles is limited only by the resolution of the data set which is 51 meters.</horizpar>			</horizpa>		</posacc>		<lineage>			<srcinfo>				<srccite>					<citeinfo>						<origin>ESRI</origin>						<pubdate>19921001</pubdate>						<title>ArcUSA? 1:2M</title>						<edition>1</edition>						<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>						<pubinfo>							<pubplace>Redlands, California, USA</pubplace>							<publish>ESRI</publish>						</pubinfo>						<othercit>USGS Topographic Quadrangles dates of publication 1975 through 1986.</othercit>					</citeinfo>				</srccite>				<srcscale>2000000</srcscale>				<typesrc>CD?ROM</typesrc>				<srctime>					<timeinfo>						<sngdate>							<caldate>19921001</caldate>						</sngdate>					</timeinfo>					<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>				</srctime>				<srccitea>ArcUSA 1:2M</srccitea>				<srccontr>Attribute and geospatial data</srccontr>			</srcinfo>			<procstep>				<procdesc>This data set was generated from several sources: the geospatial part of this data set was mathematically generated using the ARC/INFO GRID extension.  The USGS Topographic Names Database and the Published Map Sheet Data File (T-70) were the two primary digital sources for the attributes.  Where these databases were incomplete, various published USGS map indexes were consulted to update the attributes.</procdesc>				<procdate>1992</procdate>				<srcprod>ArcUSA 1:2M</srcprod>			</procstep>			<procstep>				<procdesc>The following steps were performed by ESRI: Extracted data set from ArcUSA 1:2M.  Removed unneeded attributes.  Created ArcGIS layer file (.lyr).  Created projection file (.prj).  Ran ArcView GIS Avenue request ExportClean, and created spatial indices. Converted the data set to SDC.</procdesc>				<srcused>ArcUSA 1:2M</srcused>				<procdate>20000823</procdate>			</procstep>			<procstep>				<procdesc>The following steps were performed by ESRI: Made QUAD_NAME attribute title case.</procdesc>				<procdate>20040308</procdate>			</procstep>			<procstep>				<procdesc>The following changes were made:File name changed from topoq100 to USTopoq10010.Larger Work Citation was added.Keywords and placenames were altered to reflect FGDC standards.Use Constraints, Access, Distribution Liability, Resource, Ordering instructions, Fees, and Contact information were changed to reflect Tufts University requirements.</procdesc>				<procdate>2011112</procdate>				<proccont>					<cntinfo>						<cntorgp>							<cntorg>Tufts University GIS Center</cntorg>						</cntorgp>						<cntpos>GIS Data Technician</cntpos>						<cntaddr>							<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>							<address>Academic Technology</address>							<address>16 Dearborn Rd</address>							<city>Somerville</city>							<state>MA</state>							<postal>02144</postal>							<country>USA</country>						</cntaddr>						<cntvoice>617-627-3380</cntvoice>						<cntemail>gis-support@elist.tufts.edu</cntemail>						<hours>Monday-Friday, 9:00 AM- 5:00 PM, EST-USA</hours>					</cntinfo>				</proccont>			</procstep>			<procstep>				<procdesc>Dataset copied.</procdesc>				<srcused></srcused>				<procdate>20120511</procdate>				<proctime>16092000</proctime>			</procstep>		</lineage>	</dataqual>	<spdoinfo>		<direct>Vector</direct>		<ptvctinf>			<sdtsterm Name="USTopoq1007592">				<sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>				<ptvctcnt>1809</ptvctcnt>			</sdtsterm>			<esriterm Name="USTopoq1007592"><efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp><efeageom Sync="TRUE">Polygon</efeageom><esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo><efeacnt Sync="TRUE">1809</efeacnt><spindex Sync="TRUE">TRUE</spindex><linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer></esriterm></ptvctinf>	</spdoinfo>	<spref>		<horizsys>			<geograph>				<latres>0.000009</latres>				<longres>0.000009</longres>				<geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>			</geograph>			<geodetic>				<horizdn>This data set was mathematically generated. You can define or use it unchanged with data based on any datum. Topographic maps are available based on either NAD 1927 or NAD 1983. Sheets on different datums may not line up or match the index sheets.</horizdn>				<ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>				<semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>				<denflat>298.257224</denflat>			</geodetic>			<cordsysn><geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_WGS_1984</geogcsn></cordsysn></horizsys>	</spref>	<eainfo>		<detailed Name="USTopoq1007592">			<enttyp>				<enttypl>topoq100</enttypl>				<enttypd>The polygons represent a systematic grid of 30- by 60-minute quadrangles based on a latitude-longitude graticule for the coterminous U.S. forty-eight states and District of Columbia.  Each 30- by 60-minute quadrangle is thirty-two times the area of a USGS 1:24,000 topographic quadrangle and one-fourth of a USGS 1:250,000 topographic quadrangle.</enttypd>				<enttypds>United States Geological Survey</enttypds>				<enttypt Sync="TRUE">Feature Class</enttypt><enttypc Sync="TRUE">1809</enttypc></enttyp>			<attr>				<attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>				<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>				<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">FID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">OID</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>			<attr>				<attrlabl>ObjectID</attrlabl>				<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">ObjectID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Number</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">9</attwidth></attr>			<attr>				<attrlabl>USGS_QD_ID</attrlabl>				<attrdef>The quadrangle identification number.  The first two digits represent the latitude in degrees north, the next three digits represent the longitude in degrees west, and a hyphen, and the last two characters reveal the grid cell code within each one-degree rectangle.  To understand the grid cell code within the one-degree rectangle, imagine a rectangle the shape of a door.  Divide the "door" into eight rows (A-H) and columns (1-8), the lower right corner grid cell code is "A1" and the upper left corner grid cell code is "H8".  Each grid cell represents a USGS 1:24,000 topographic quadrangle, hence sixty-four per one-degree rectangle.  Each USGS 1:100,000 topographic quadrangle is one-half by one degree with only two fitting within the one-degree rectangle-the upper half and the lower half of the "door".  The lower quadrangle's grid cell code is "A1" and the upper quadrangle's grid cell code is "E1" (these are the only grid cell codes for USGS 1:100,000 topographic quadrangles).  Each USGS 1:250,000 topographic quadrangle is one by two degrees, which, is two "doors" side by side.  The quadrangle's grid cell code is "A1" (this is the only grid cell code for USGS 1:250,000 topographic quadrangles).</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Geological Survey (U.S.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<codesetd>						<codesetn>USGS Topographic Names Database, Published Map Sheet Data File (T-70)</codesetn>						<codesets>Geological Survey (U.S.)</codesets>					</codesetd>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">USGS_QD_ID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">8</attwidth></attr>			<attr>				<attrlabl>QUAD_NAME</attrlabl>				<attrdef>The quadrangle name.</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Geological Survey (U.S.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<udom>Names for the features.</udom>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">QUAD_NAME</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">32</attwidth></attr>			<attr>				<attrlabl>MAP_EDIT</attrlabl>				<attrdef>The type of map for the quadrangle.  If several types of maps exist for the same quadrangle, the lowest code value is listed.</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Geological Survey (U.S.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<edom>						<edomv>1</edomv>						<edomvd>Topographic contour.</edomvd>						<edomvds>Geological Survey (U.S.)</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>3</edomv>						<edomvd>Planimetric.</edomvd>						<edomvds>Geological Survey (U.S.)</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>G</edomv>						<edomvd>Surface management status (Bureau of Land Management)</edomvd>						<edomvds>Geological Survey (U.S.)</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>H</edomv>						<edomvd>Surface minerals (Bureau of Land Management)</edomvd>						<edomvds>Geological Survey (U.S.)</edomvds>					</edom>					<edom>						<edomv>K</edomv>						<edomvd>Topographybathymetry, line map.</edomvd>						<edomvds>Geological Survey (U.S.)</edomvds>					</edom>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">MAP_EDIT</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">1</attwidth></attr>			<attr>				<attrlabl>ST_NAME1</attrlabl>				<attrdef>The name of the state in which the quadrangle is located. The state names are always stored beginning with ST_NAME1, but they are not listed in any particular order.</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Geological Survey (U.S.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<codesetd>						<codesetn>Federal Information Processing Standards</codesetn>						<codesets>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</codesets>					</codesetd>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">ST_NAME1</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">20</attwidth></attr>			<attr>				<attrlabl>ST_NAME2</attrlabl>				<attrdef>The name of the second state in which the quadrangle is located. The state names are always stored beginning with ST_NAME1, but they are not listed in any particular order. If a quadrangle covers fewer than four states, this attribute may be blank.</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Geological Survey (U.S.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<codesetd>						<codesetn>Federal Information Processing Standards</codesetn>						<codesets>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</codesets>					</codesetd>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">ST_NAME2</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">20</attwidth></attr>			<attr>				<attrlabl>ST_NAME3</attrlabl>				<attrdef>The name of the third state in which the quadrangle is located. The state names are always stored beginning with ST_NAME1, but they are not listed in any particular order. If a quadrangle covers fewer than four states, this attribute may be blank.</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Geological Survey (U.S.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<codesetd>						<codesetn>Federal Information Processing Standards</codesetn>						<codesets>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</codesets>					</codesetd>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">ST_NAME3</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">20</attwidth></attr>			<attr>				<attrlabl>ST_NAME4</attrlabl>				<attrdef>The name of the fourth state in which the quadrangle is located. The state names are always stored beginning with ST_NAME1, but they are not listed in any particular order. If a quadrangle covers fewer than four states, this attribute may be blank.</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Geological Survey (U.S.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<codesetd>						<codesetn>Federal Information Processing Standards</codesetn>						<codesets>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</codesets>					</codesetd>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">ST_NAME4</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">20</attwidth></attr>			<attr>				<attrlabl>DATE_PUB</attrlabl>				<attrdef>The most recent date of publication for the quadrangle, expressed as the last two digits of the year in the twentieth century.</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Geological Survey (U.S.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<udom>Dates for the features.</udom>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">DATE_PUB</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">2</attwidth></attr>			<attr>				<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>				<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>				<attrdefs>Environmental Systems Research Institute (Redlands, Calif.)</attrdefs>				<attrdomv>					<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>				</attrdomv>				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Geometry</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>		</detailed>	</eainfo>	<distinfo>		<distrib>			<cntinfo>				<cntorgp>					<cntorg>Tufts University GIS Center</cntorg>				</cntorgp>				<cntpos>Data Technician</cntpos>				<cntaddr>					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>					<address>Academic Technology</address>					<address>16 Dearborn Rd</address>					<city>Somerville</city>					<state>MA</state>					<postal>02144</postal>					<country>USA</country>				</cntaddr>				<cntvoice>617-627-3380</cntvoice>				<cntemail>gis-support@elist.tufts.edu</cntemail>				<hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 5:00 pm EST-USA</hours>			</cntinfo>		</distrib>		<resdesc>Online Dataset</resdesc>		<distliab>Although this data is being distributed by Tufts University, no warranty expressed or implied is made by the University as to the accuracy of the data and related materials. The act of distribution shall not constitute any such warranty, and no responsibility is assumed by the University in the use of this data, or related materials.</distliab>		<stdorder>			<digform>				<digtinfo>					<formname>SDC</formname>					<formspec>The SDC file contains the geospatial and attribute data. The SDI file contains the spatial index. The PRJ file contains the coordinate system information (optional). The XML file (*.sdc.xml) contains the metadata describing the data set (optional).</formspec>					<filedec>ArcGIS software</filedec>					<transize>0.282</transize>					<dssize Sync="TRUE">1.448</dssize></digtinfo>				<digtopt>					<offoptn>						<offmedia>DVD?ROM</offmedia>						<reccap>							<recden>4.38 or 7.95</recden>							<recdenu>GB (gigabytes)</recdenu>						</reccap>						<recfmt>UDF (Universal Disc Format)</recfmt>					</offoptn>				</digtopt>			</digform>			<fees>none</fees>			<ordering>Web-based Distribution Only.</ordering>		</stdorder>		<techpreq>To use this data requires software that supports SDC files.</techpreq>	</distinfo>	<metainfo>		<metd>20120502</metd>		<metc>			<cntinfo>				<cntorgp>					<cntorg>Tufts University GIS Center</cntorg>				</cntorgp>				<cntpos>Data Technician</cntpos>				<cntaddr>					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>					<address>Academic Technology</address>					<address>16 Dearborn Rd</address>					<city>Somerville</city>					<state>MA</state>					<postal>02144</postal>					<country>USA</country>				</cntaddr>				<cntvoice>617-627-3380</cntvoice>				<cntemail>gis-supports@elits.tufts.edu</cntemail>				<hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 5:00 pm EST-USA</hours>			</cntinfo>		</metc>		<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>		<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>		<mettc>local time</mettc>		<metextns>			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>		</metextns>		<metextns>			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>		</metextns>		<langmeta Sync="TRUE">en</langmeta><metextns><onlink Sync="TRUE">http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink><metprof Sync="TRUE">ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof></metextns></metainfo>	<Esri><ModDate>20120717</ModDate><ModTime>10325200</ModTime><SyncDate>20120717</SyncDate><SyncTime>10325200</SyncTime></Esri><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20120717</mdDateSt><dataIdInfo><envirDesc Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows Vista Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.4000</envirDesc><dataLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en"></languageCode></dataLang><idCitation><resTitle Sync="TRUE">USTopoq1007592</resTitle><presForm><PresFormCd Sync="TRUE" value="005"></PresFormCd></presForm></idCitation><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></SpatRepTypCd></spatRpType><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox esriExtentType="native"><westBL Sync="TRUE">-125.000027</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-66.000005</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">49.500002</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">24.5</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt><geoBox esriExtentType="decdegrees"><westBL Sync="TRUE">-125.000027</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-66.000005</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">49.500002</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">24.5</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></geoBox></dataIdInfo><mdLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en"></languageCode></mdLang><mdStanName Sync="TRUE">ISO 19115 Geographic Information - Metadata</mdStanName><mdStanVer Sync="TRUE">DIS_ESRI1.0</mdStanVer><mdChar><CharSetCd Sync="TRUE" value="004"></CharSetCd></mdChar><mdHrLv><ScopeCd Sync="TRUE" value="005"></ScopeCd></mdHrLv><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName><distInfo><distributor><distorTran><onLineSrc><orDesc Sync="TRUE">002</orDesc><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\rstore2\gisprojects$\GIS_Center_Projects\EnterpriseGIS\Layers\ESRIDataaandMaps 10\esri shapefiles\USTopoq1007592.shp</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></onLineSrc><transSize Sync="TRUE">1.448</transSize></distorTran><distorFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><refSysInfo><RefSystem><refSysID><identCode Sync="TRUE">GCS_WGS_1984</identCode></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo><spatRepInfo><VectSpatRep><topLvl><TopoLevCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></TopoLevCd></topLvl><geometObjs Name="USTopoq1007592"><geoObjTyp><GeoObjTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></GeoObjTypCd></geoObjTyp><geoObjCnt Sync="TRUE">1809</geoObjCnt></geometObjs></VectSpatRep></spatRepInfo></metadata>